<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>Tom Ray</title>
 <link href="http://tmray.github.io//atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://tmray.github.io//"/>
 <updated>2015-07-13T19:19:37+00:00</updated>
 <id>http://tmray.github.io/</id>
 <author>
   <name>Tom Ray</name>
   <email>tmray1@gmail.com</email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>Fascinated By Deja Vu</title>
   <link href="http://tmray.github.io//2015/07/13/fascinated-by-deja-vu/"/>
   <updated>2015-07-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>http://tmray.github.io//2015/07/13/fascinated-by-deja-vu</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I’m fascinated by deja vu. (see what I did there?)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It happens to me a lot. And while reading about it this afternoon there are of course many different theories as to why it happens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One theory says it’s connected to epilepsy. But I don’t know anybody that’s said they’ve never experienced it in one way or another. So that can’t be right can it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“The strongest pathological association of deja vu is with temporal lobe epilepsy. This correlation has led some researchers to speculate that the experience of deja vu is possibly a neurological anomaly related to improper electrical discharge in the brain.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;cite&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/D%C3%A9j%C3%A0_vu#Links_with_disorders&quot;&gt;— Deja vu - Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think the concept of studying something that you can’t clearly show other people is amazing. You can only describe what it is like to you. You don’t REALLY know what it is until you’ve experienced it. Like explaining being in love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it happens to me I find myself just trying to figure out what it was that it reminds me of. Like seeing an actor in a movie that you recognize, but just can’t place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And when you experience it, are you like me and think it’s some big premonition? Something on another level is trying to tell you something? Why is that? Why does it always have to mean something?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think it’s just the spookiness of the “second site” that’s had. Tells you it must mean something. Why would such a unique experience be wasted on something that means nothing?&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Being Too Close To Know It</title>
   <link href="http://tmray.github.io//2015/07/12/Being-Too-Close-To-Know-It/"/>
   <updated>2015-07-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>http://tmray.github.io//2015/07/12/Being-Too-Close-To-Know-It</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm6.staticflickr.com/5615/15552968635_ba8c975a28_z.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Nina Simone&quot; /&gt;
   &lt;cite&gt;CC-BY-SA Some rights reserved by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/bionicteaching/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;bionicteaching&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Watched the Netflix documentary of Nina Simone the other night. I love watching a good music doc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In it she talks about learning and wanting to be the first African-American female classical pianist. Later in life, because of money she has to take job as a nightclub act.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then she was discovered and continued to do music in this genre from there on. Always wishing that she could go back to the other dream.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As they played songs from this timeline in the story she even talked about how she grew to hate it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you listen to what she does it is like nothing at the time. What she knows to do and just the way she does things is so different from what someone else would have done with the songs. And it made me sad that she didn’t seem to get that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the time came of the civil rights movement she wrote a song called “Mississippi Goddam”. Leading up to this I thought I knew exactly what this song was going to sound like. I was wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/fVQjGGJVSXc?rel=0&amp;amp;showinfo=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The song is fast. It is bouncy. And it is aggressive. I don’t think anyone could write the way they felt that she did here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s why I say sometimes an artist can be too close to what they do to realize just what they bring to the craft. It just sounds like a song to them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think this is why musicians have such a hard time answering the question: What kind of music do you play?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ask others. Have those that know you tell you what it sounds like and means to them.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Keeping With Connections</title>
   <link href="http://tmray.github.io//2015/07/11/Keeping-With-Connections/"/>
   <updated>2015-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>http://tmray.github.io//2015/07/11/Keeping-With-Connections</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;One of the reasons I started the podcast I do, &lt;a href=&quot;http://musicmanumit.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Music Manumit&lt;/a&gt;, is to learn more about creative commons music and meet other like minded people that do the same thing. And I have. I’ve meet so many that I don’t remember all of them off the top of my head. And that’s a problem.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/wN2OV9vus9zsz3MtRg32F48HeniBlALjLFcT3jq4bxua=w184-h183-no&quot; style=&quot;float:left; margin: 10px 20px 10px 0px;&quot; /&gt;
Friday I talked with the new head of the site &lt;a href=&quot;http://freemusicarchive.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;free music archive&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Cheyenne Hohman&lt;/strong&gt;, who is a great person and has done a lot for the site in the time that she’s been there. Though promotion, reaching out to people and reinvigorating the &lt;a href=&quot;http://freemusicarchive.org/tag/radio_free_culture/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;radio free culture podcast&lt;/a&gt;. Talking to her inspired me. Which is the whole point of doing interviews with people like her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve talked to the last 3 people in her position at the site over the years and not kept in touch. why? I didn’t even know until we scheduled the interview with Cheyenne that Andrea, the previous person had left.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have connections with so many of these people that I need to get better at keeping in touch. Talking to them about like minded projects and collaborating with them. Bring them in on ideas i have, because they, as I mentioned, are doing what I am too– getting their stuff out there and wanting people to create from it &amp;amp; with it. We should all keep connected. Why wouldn’t we?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First try at doing this was a cover of a song my band &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lorenzosmusic.com/2015/06/stampede-biting-elbows-cover.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Lorenzo/&#39;s Music: Stampede - Biting Elbows Cover&quot;&gt;Lorenzo’s Music&lt;/a&gt; made of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.jamendo.com/en/track/784184/the-stampede&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Biting Elbows: The Stampede&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Biting Elbows&lt;/strong&gt; song “Stampede”&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/cUrxzrRYJXQ?rel=0&amp;amp;showinfo=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I had the singer &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.musicmanumit.com/2015/01/biting-elbows-150118-music-manumit.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ilya Naishuller&lt;/strong&gt; on the podcast before&lt;/a&gt; and I thought it would be a good start. After doing recording and live video of the song, I shared a link with him and he shared it to his people too. Being a creative commons song (cc-by-nc-sa) we were able to do this, no worries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even this little bit of our connection made it a very successful experiment. After that others that saw contacted me to use the song we did in their own way with their projects. Like we did.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I need to keep in touch more with people I meet or what’s the point of doing?&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Marketing in your own voice</title>
   <link href="http://tmray.github.io//2015/07/10/Marketing-in-your-own-voice/"/>
   <updated>2015-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>http://tmray.github.io//2015/07/10/Marketing-in-your-own-voice</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I’m not necessarily a shy person. I can get in front of people, make a jackass of myself. No problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being a musician, a podcaster &amp;amp; artist I am comfortable with personal work out there in front of people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I do those things I know what I like, how I sound and what I want to do. What I think works and what don’t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s the thing. After all of that is done, need to promote to show people. I know where I want it to be seen and done the work to get it there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I try to tell people they should see it and why- with advertisement or social post, I never know what to say. And it always sounds phony.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hell, get me in a room with people and I’m not shy starting conversations. Why should this part be so hard? I assume this is same reason why not everyone can act. Seems insincere when I do it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I’m trying to find that voice. Trying to be able to be myself, even when I’m trying to convince people for the first time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope I find why this stupid thing gives such anxiety?&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Collaboration... Give or Take</title>
   <link href="http://tmray.github.io//2015/07/09/Collaboration-Give-or-Take/"/>
   <updated>2015-07-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>http://tmray.github.io//2015/07/09/Collaboration-Give-or-Take</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/HLpGVedwt8Xs5o4jw2b8lCqC7ONKej4tUKgyB1ACGZRR=s650-no&quot; alt=&quot;Frank - the movie&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my work-a-day, 9to5 life I don’t like to collaborate with people. Meaning, I do something and don’t look for opinion. Not really wanting or need example of another way to do what I did. And its not a secret. Maybe you can relate?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently watched the movie “Frank”. About a musician looking for stardom. Finds band that just lost a member and singer has giant paper mache head. You know, the norm.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00NBNY7P2/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B00NBNY7P2&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=lorsmus-20&amp;amp;linkId=PPZW7NNE3FK57NSP&quot; style=&quot;clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://ws-na.amazon-adsystem.com/widgets/q?_encoding=UTF8&amp;amp;ASIN=B00NBNY7P2&amp;amp;Format=_SL250_&amp;amp;ID=AsinImage&amp;amp;MarketPlace=US&amp;amp;ServiceVersion=20070822&amp;amp;WS=1&amp;amp;tag=lorsmus-20&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://ir-na.amazon-adsystem.com/e/ir?t=lorsmus-20&amp;amp;l=as2&amp;amp;o=1&amp;amp;a=B00NBNY7P2&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;border: none !important; margin: 0px !important;&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;
Our protagonist, the new musician to the group, shows them song he’s working on. 
They like the idea then step in front of his keyboard and start suggesting, do this or try this as he stands behind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My Wife turns to me and says “that must drive you nuts!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You would think. Given what I said before by all means I should hate that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I don’t. Not in that situation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe because creatively I work with like minds I respect and choose to be around. I know they’ll make what I do better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Work life: you don’t choose people. They’re just there. And end of day I would rather be done doing that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make things with people I want to make them with, I care more.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>The Simplest Ah-ha Moments Can Change Everything</title>
   <link href="http://tmray.github.io//2015/07/08/The-Simplest-Ah-ha-Moments-Can-Change-Everything/"/>
   <updated>2015-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>http://tmray.github.io//2015/07/08/The-Simplest-Ah-ha-Moments-Can-Change-Everything</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I love when realization happens. Something simple that takes a mundane task or thing you do over &amp;amp; over to a sense of disbelief. Because of something stupid you just didn’t think to do. Your world changes. So many possibilities. All because you were shown something.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This I love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is a current example. Podcasts, I have so many to listen to. I don’t have time to hear all the ones I want to hear. Would need to stop listening to one to replace another just to fit it in. Told a friend this when he recommended a new one to me. Then he says– “that’s why I speed listen to mine”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What the hell is that? Tells me it’s like speed reading but with audio. Turn the player speed up to 2x and you can fit more in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I never would have thought of that!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sure it takes a few minutes to adjust to the way it sounds, but it changes everything. Not bogged down with overwhelming playlist anymore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the type of thing to remember.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you do something, share how its done. Even if it seems like it’s obvious and you tell yourself, “everyone must already know this”? Because someone is always new at something somewhere and you may just open their eyes to a whole different opportunity.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Glass Half-Full Weather Half-Empty</title>
   <link href="http://tmray.github.io//2015/07/07/Glass-Half-Full-Weather-Half-Empty/"/>
   <updated>2015-07-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>http://tmray.github.io//2015/07/07/Glass-Half-Full-Weather-Half-Empty</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7338/16295109489_17602bd8d9_c.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;
&lt;cite&gt;Attribution Share Alike Some rights reserved by &lt;a href=&quot;https://flic.kr/p/qPWGkB&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Urban_Integration&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t know what it is, but I wait and I wait for summer and feel like it’s never going to come. And when it does it seems like a 3 day weekend that’s almost over to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe it’s because I’ve lived in the Midwest my whole life and dread winter as time goes on? July 4 was the first day that felt like summer and historically from days of school it was the beginning of the end. It meant vacation was close to ending. And what have I done by this milestone I always ask?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The strange thing is most times I am very much an “anything is possible” type of person. when weather is the subject I am not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Weather is a great mood for music. Making things sound like Halloween or gray cold air. And thinking back on times when things seemed that way may put imagery in ones head. Anticipating actual climate change is what I don’t look forward to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-winter-sounds-like&quot;&gt;What winter sounds like:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tom Waits - The Black Rider&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B000W29AXO/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B000W29AXO&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=lorsmus-20&amp;amp;linkId=2Q5XW2LBB5O3SNCE&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://ws-na.amazon-adsystem.com/widgets/q?_encoding=UTF8&amp;amp;ASIN=B000W29AXO&amp;amp;Format=_SL250_&amp;amp;ID=AsinImage&amp;amp;MarketPlace=US&amp;amp;ServiceVersion=20070822&amp;amp;WS=1&amp;amp;tag=lorsmus-20&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://ir-na.amazon-adsystem.com/e/ir?t=lorsmus-20&amp;amp;l=as2&amp;amp;o=1&amp;amp;a=B000W29AXO&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; style=&quot;border:none !important; margin:0px !important;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Just a Placeholder</title>
   <link href="http://tmray.github.io//2015/07/06/just-a-placeholder/"/>
   <updated>2015-07-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>http://tmray.github.io//2015/07/06/just-a-placeholder</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The official v0.2 post for the new blog set up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More later.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Mobile post</title>
   <link href="http://tmray.github.io//2015/07/06/Mobile-post/"/>
   <updated>2015-07-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>http://tmray.github.io//2015/07/06/Mobile-post</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;testing-out-a-mobile-posting-app&quot;&gt;Testing out a mobile posting app&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;trying out the android mobile app MrHyde just to see how it works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7327/9635872528_97a8cf902a_c.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; title=&quot;cat, what you looking at?&quot; /&gt;
&lt;cite&gt;— AttributionShare Alike Some rights reserved by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/carianoff/9635872528/in/photolist-fFuncf-7rNLdi&quot; title=&quot;6D wifi test&quot;&gt;carianoff&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>
